Right now we see a picture of a phone.
지금 휴대전화의 사진을 확인합니다.
But this isn't actually on our phone.
하지만, 사진이 휴대전화에 보이지 않습니다.
This is pretty similar to when we were working with the XML visualizer.
이는 XML 비주얼라이저를 사용할 때 비슷하게 작용합니다.
Now we actually want to see our app on our phone.
이제 우리는 우리 전화기에서 앱을 보고자 하는데요.
To participate, you're going to need a USB cable like this.
이 활동을 위해 우리는 이것같은 USB 케이블이 필요해요.
Now this USB cable should fit your Android phone, which you will also need.
이 USB 케이블은 안드로이드 전화에 맞아야 되는 데 그것도 필요해요.
What do I mean by fit?
맞다는 게 무슨의미냐구요?
Well, I can pick up my phone and plug this cable into it.
휴대전화를 잡고 케이블을 전화기에 연결하는 것입니다.
Now if you don't have these things,
이제 이 설명이 필요하지 않다면,
there's a slightly more complicated way you can get up and running.
이제 설정하고 실행하는 방법은 조금 복잡합니다.
Which I'm going to talk about in the next video.
다음 비디오에 이야기하고자 하는 사항이 있습니다.
But, if you have both of these items,
하지만 이 항목들이 다 있다면
I really encourage you to use a real device, its a lot more fun that way.
실제로 사용되며 재미있다고 이야기 하고싶습니다.
All right.
네
First things, first.
첫번째로
Your phone is not set up to let random code from your computer run on your
당신의 휴대전화는 아무 코드를 휴대폰 설정에 따라
phone by default.
설정하게 하지 않습니다.
So you're going to need to do a few steps to prep your phone.
그래서, 당신은 휴대전화를 준비할 필요가 있습니다.
Okay, so the first step is to become a developer.
이제 개발자가 되는 단계입니다.
This sounds a little funny, when would you know when you're a developer?
이는 즐겁고, 개발자가 된다고 느껴보세요
Well, what this actually means is changing around a couple of settings on
실제로 몇가지 설정사항을
the phone, which will alow you to access developer options.
개발자 설정에서 변경해줍니다.
Once your phone's set up, you'll connect your phone to your computer
휴대전화가 설정된다면, 당신은 휴대전화를 컴퓨터에
using the USB cable that I talked about before.
먼저 언급한 USB 케이블을 이용하여 연결합니다.
Now if you're using a Windows machine, the third step for
이제, 윈도우를 이용하여
you, in Windows only, will be to install a driver.
세가지 단계를 통해 윈도우를 위한 드라이버를 설치하죠.
And a driver is an extra little bit of software that will allow your
드라이버는 추가사항이이며 휴대전화가
phone to communicate with your Windows machine.
당신의 윈도우 시스템과 호환할 수 있도록 돕습니다.
With Macs, this just works by default, so you don't have to worry about it.
Macs인 경우 단지 초기설정이라 걱정할 필요가 없습니다.
And finally, you'll install your app.
마침내 인스톨을 합니다.
Alright, let's stop doing these steps.
이 단계를 그만 하고
On newer phones, running Android 4.2 and later,
새로운 휴대전화 안드로이드 4.2 이상은
you'll need to tell your phone you're a developer.
휴대전화에 앱 개발자라는 사실을 알려야합니다.
This is a pretty simple process that I'll show you right now.
이는 매우 간단한 작업이며, 지금 보여드리겠습니다.
The way to do this is to navigate to the Settings menu.
이 방법은 설정 메뉴로 이동하여
Once you're here, scroll down to the bottom and click on About phone.
스크롤을 아래로 내려 휴대전화 정보를 클릭합니다.
On this menu, also scroll down to the bottom.
이 메뉴에서 스크롤을 아래로 내립니다.
You should see something that says Build number.
빌드 숫자를 보실 수 있습니다.
Okay, so take the build number and click it 7 times.
빌드 숫자를 확인후 7번 클릭합니다.
Cool.
좋습니다.
So now suddenly, you're a developer.
이제 당신은 앱 개발자입니다.
Wasn't that easy?
쉽지 않았나요?
Once you're done, go ahead and hit the back button.
완성했으면, 이제 뒤로가기를 누르세요.
Now because of your new fancy title as a developer, you should notice that
이제 새로운 이름인 개발자로
the phone has provided you with a new option, the developer options.
당신은 새로운 설정 및 개발자 설정을 사용할 수 있죠.
Go ahead and click on that.
클릭해보세요.
Okay, now in developer options there's a bunch of fancy sounding options, but
좋습니다, 이제 개발자 설정에서 다양한 음향 설정이 있습니다,
what I want you to do is scroll down until you see USB debugging.
이곳에서 하고자 하는 것은
And say OK.
그리고 '네'를 클릭하세요.
By checking this box,
이 박스를 설정함으로
it's allowing your computer to put applications onto your phone.
이는 당신의 휴대전화에 앱과 컴퓨터를 연결해줍니다.
Awesome.
좋습니다.
Now that you've enabled that,
이제 작동시켰으니,
you can take your handy dandy USB cable, plug one end into the phone, and
USB 케이블을 다시 꺼내 휴대전화에 연결하고
take the other end and plug it into your computer.
다른 한 부분을 컴퓨터에 연결해주세요.
If you're on a Windows device,
윈도우 장치를 사용하신다면,
there's one more step to set up your phone and computer.
휴대전화와 컴퓨터를 연결하기 위한 한가지 단계가 더 남아있습니다.
Your Windows machine needs some software called the driver to communicate
당신의 윈도우 장치는 휴대전화와 연결을 위해
with your phone.
소프트웨어를 설치해야하는데요
I'll start by downloading the driver.
드라이버를 다운로드하고
For most phones besides Google Nexus phones,
구글 넥서스를 제외한 다른 휴대전화는
you can navigate to the Android OEM, which stands for
Android OEM,
original equipment manufacturers, driver website.
즉, 휴대전화 제조사의 웹사이트에서 확인하실 수 있습니다.
A link is provided in the instructor notes.
링크는 사용 설명서에 적혀있습니다.
I'm going to scroll down to the bottom.
이제 아래쪽으로 이동하여
Here I have a list of drivers for different phones, and
각 다른 휴대전화의 드라이버 목록을 확인하고
I will go ahead and download the appropriate one.
알맞는 드라이버를 다운로드 하겠습니다.
In my case, I have a nexus phone, so
제 경우에는 넥서스를 사용하므로,
I'm going to go up on the page, and click google USB driver.
페이지로 가서 구글 USB 드라이버를 클릭합니다.
This is again, for Nexus phones.
이 방법은 Nexus폰을 위한 것입니다.
Okay, so for me, I'm going to go ahead and download the google USB driver,
저는 이동하여 바로 구글 USB 드라이버를 다운로드 할 수 있죠.
Unzip it, I'm going to move this to my desktop.
압축을 풀고 데스크탑에 저장합니다.
So at this point, I've downloaded the driver, i've unzipped it and
이제 드라이버를 다운로드하고 압축을 풀고
I've put it on my desktop.
데스크탑에 옮겨넣습니다.
What you need to do next is double check that your phone is actually plugged in.
이제 할 일은 휴대전화가 연결되어 있는지 확인하는 거죠.
Okay let's look at our task bar.
태스크바를 확인하면
I'm going to click on the start menu and go to computer.
시작메뉴를 클릭하고 컴퓨터로 갑니다.
In Windows Explorer I'm going to right-click on the word here that
윈도우 익스플로러에서 우측 클릭을 하면
says computer.
컴퓨터라고 있는데요
In this left pane here, I'm going to select device manager, so
이 부분 왼쪽에서 장치관리자로 간 후,
looking through this list, go ahead and
리스트를 확인한 다음
find the thing that says other devices and expand it.
다른 장치 및 확장을 찾습니다.
Now you should see something here that refers to your phone.
이제 당신은 휴대전화를 보여주는 표시를 찾을 수 있을 것입니다.
For example, NexusS, or ADB,
예를들어, NexusS 혹은 ADB
OK. Okay, so I'm going to right-click and
오케이. 이제 우측 클릭을 하고
select update driver software.
장치 소프트웨어 업데이트를 합니다.
This is going to launch a wizard that looks like this, and
이는 이와같은 마법사 화면을 보여줄 것이고,
I want to select the one that let's me browse my computer, because remember,
컴퓨터에서 파일을 확인할 수 있게 선택을 설정할 것입니다
I just downloaded it to my desktop.
파일을 컴퓨터에 저장했다는 걸 기억해 주세요
I'm going to do browse computer, and I'm going to go ahead and click browse.
컴퓨터를 확인하고 검색을 클릭합니다.
And I'm going to go to my desktop and hit OK and hit next.
그리고 데스크탑에 가서 네 버튼을 클릭후 이동합니다.
I might see some security messages like this.
아마 보안 경고 메세지를 볼 수도 있습니다.
Go ahead and say, install.
진행하여 설치하도록 명령하세요.
All right. Cool.
좋습니다. 잘했어요.
So, this autoplay just popped up with my Nexus 6, so that's a good sign
이제 자동적으로 제 Nexus 6는 작동하고 있습니다.
that now the computer's communicating well with my phone.
이제 휴대전화와 컴퓨터가 동기화되었네요.
I'm going to go ahead and close this.
이제 이 화면을 닫습니다.
And the final window of the wizard,
그리고 설치마법사에서
says that Windows has successfully updated your driver software.
윈도우에 성공적으로 설치되었으며 소프트웨어를 업데이트 하라고 하죠.
So that sounds awesome.
굉장히 좋게 들리네요.
Go ahead and click close.
이제 창을 닫으세요.
Basically at this point,
이 시점에서는
your phone is ready to accept the application from your computer.
당신의 휴대전화는 이미 컴퓨터에서 앱 사용을 허가 받은 것입니다.
Another way of saying that you can now install apps that
앱을 설치하는 다른 방법은
you've built on your computer, onto your phone.
컴퓨터에 설치하여 휴대전화로 옮기는 건데요.
Finally, were going to install our Hello World App from the computer
이제 저희는 Hello World앱을 컴퓨터에서 설치하여
onto the phone.
휴대전화로 옮기겠습니다.
To do this, you're going to go up to the top of Android Studio
이것을 위해 개발자는 안드로이드 스튜디오를 확인해야하는데요.
to this green play button, and click it.
녹색 시작 버튼입니다. 클릭하세요.
It will take about ten seconds or so for the next window to pop up so be patient.
이는 10초 정도 걸리며 다음 윈도우 창이 열릴때 까지 기다리세요.
you should be able to see that there's some process being executed.
당신은 이제 과정이 완료된 것을 확인할 수 있습니다.
Now, if everything went as planned, your computer should detect your phone and
이제, 계획된대로 진행되었다면, 당신의 컴퓨터는 휴대전화를 탐지하고
list it here.
이곳에 표시할 것입니다.
Make sure you have the Choose a running device radio button clicked and
사용중인 디바이스 버튼을 클릭하는 것을 확인하시고
not the Launch emulator radio button selected.
에물레이터가 아닌 라디오 버튼을 클릭하세요.
If you can't see your phone, try unplugging it and re-plugging it in.
휴대전화를 확인할 수 없다면 다시 연결해보세요.
And then try restarting the phone.
그리고 휴대전화를 재시작하세요.
If that also doesn't work and
혹시 작동하지 않는다면
you're on a Windows machine, you might have installed the wrong driver.
윈도우 장치에서는, 잘못된 드라이버를 설치하였을지도 모르죠.
If none of those solutions seem to solve your problem, we've created
이 중 어느 것도 문제를 해결하지 못한다면,
And you can always try asking your fellow students for help on chat or
주변 학생들에게 채팅으로 도움을 요청하시거나
in forums.
게시판에 글을 남겨주셔도 됩니다.
Okay, but hopefully things are working.
이제 모든 것이 작동했으면 하네요.
You can select your phone and click the OK button.
휴대전화를 선택하고 오케이 버튼을 클릭하세요.
After about five seconds you should see your phone looks like this.
5초 후에 당신은 휴대전화를 다음과 같이 보실 수 있습니다.
You've now successfully run your first android application on a phone.
이제 당신은 성공적으로 첫번째 안드로이드 앱을 폰에 실행시킨 것이죠.
Awesome work.
잘하셨어요.
As we start thinking about our birthday card application,
이제 우리 생일카드 앱을 생각하며,
I want you to think about a friend who's having a birthday that's coming up.
저는 생일이 다가오는 친구를 생각하고 싶네요.
Now, my challenge to you is to change the app that we currently have
이제 현재 우리가 가진 앱을 이용하여
to say happy birthday and then that person's name,
생일축하 메세지를 남기고 이름을 남기고자 합니다
and then to run that app on your phone.
그리고 앱을 휴대전화에 실행시켜보겠습니다.
Remember, you'll need to change the main activity .xml code file
기억하세요, 당신은 아마 주요 활동인 .xml 코드 파일을
the same way we practiced changing code in the Internet browser.
같은 방법으로 인터넷 창에서 변경해야 합니다.
Right now the text says hello world, but you should be able to find the correct
이제 텍스트는" hello world" 표시하지만, 이제 알맞는
attribute to change it to say, Happy Birthday and then your friend's name.
문장인 생일축하 메세지와 친구의 이름을 설정하여야합니다.
After you've done that, press the green run button and
설정 이후에, 초록 실행버튼을 클릭하고
install the app on your phone.
앱을 휴대전화에 설치해보세요.
Good luck.
행운을 빕니다.